[ukulele music]
[尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[background chattering]
[背景窃窃私语]
Order for...
订购...
Huh?
啊？
both: Om, nom, nom.
两者：唵，名义，名义。
Ohh.
哦。
Disgusting!
恶心！
You people eat like anima...
anima...
你们这些人吃得像阿尼玛……
阿尼玛...
Anima...
Achoo!
阿尼玛...
阿呼！
[sad music]
[悲伤的音乐]
[barking]
[叫声]
Oh, there's my baby.
哦，我的宝贝在那儿。
Oh, my little baby!
哦，我的小宝贝！
Oh, no.
哦，不。
You cannot bring a worm in here.
你不能把虫子带进来。
It's unclean!
不干净啊！
And some of us are allergi...
我们中的一些人过敏...
Achoo! Bah!...gic.
阿呼！呸！……太棒了。
What's with all the sniffy
fits out here, Mr. Squidward?
所有的嗅觉是怎么回事
章鱼哥先生，这里适合吗？
It's not my fault,
Mr. Krabs.
这不是我的错
蟹老板。
She snuck a pet
into the restaurant.
她偷偷养了一只宠物
进入餐厅。
Oh, I didn't know my sweet
little Fifi wasn't allowed.
哦，我不知道我的甜蜜
小菲菲不被允许。
Aaaachoo!
啊啊啊！
Hmm?
唔？
[poof]
[panting]
[噗]
[气喘吁吁]
Well, your sweet little
Foofoo's gotta go.
嗯，你可爱的小
福福该走了。
We have a strict policy.
我们有严格的政策。
No pets allowed.
不允许携带宠物。
What a shame.
真丢脸。
Krabby Patties are all my Fifi
will eat these days.
蟹黄饼都是我的菲菲
这几天会吃。
Oh, I would have gladly paid
double the price
哦，我很乐意付钱
双倍价格
if it only meant she could have
her favorite food.
如果这仅仅意味着她可以
她最喜欢的食物。
[squeals]
[尖叫声]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Ah, there!
All fixed.
啊，在那里！
全部固定。
See?
"Now: Pets Allowed!"
看？
“现在：允许携带宠物！”
Oh!
How delightful!
哦！
多么令人愉快啊！
Of course.
当然。
Bwaa choo!
呸呸呸！
[overlapping chatter]
[重叠的喋喋不休]
[cow moos]
[牛哞哞]
Hee hee!
嘻嘻！
I tell ya, Mr. Squidward,
我告诉你，章鱼哥先生，
I'm makin' more money
than Neptune!
我要赚更多的钱
比海王星！
Hehehe!
呵呵呵呵！
Aachoo!
Bah!
啊呼！
呸!
Hmm?
唔？
Hold it right there, Krabs.
抓住它，蟹蟹。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Oh, no!
The health inspector!
哦，不！
卫生督察！
Oh, yes.
The health inspector.
哦是的。
卫生督察。
And I'm afraid you can't
run a restaurant
恐怕你不能
经营一家餐馆
and a feed lot
out of the same building!
和一个饲料场
从同一栋楼出来的！
Hee, hee.
Ha, ha!
嘿嘿。
哈，哈！
It's unsanitary.
这是不卫生的。
I'm shutting you down!
我要关掉你了！
Unless you pick one.
除非你选一个。
People or pets.
人或宠物。
Ohh.
Heh.
哦。
呵呵。
♪ ♪
♪♪
Ooh!
哦！
♪ ♪
♪♪
Ooh!
哦！
Oh, yeah!
哦，是啊！
I choose pets!
我选择宠物！
Heh, ha!
呵呵！
What?!
No!
什么？！
不！
All right, you heard the man.
好吧，你听到了那个人的话。
If you ain't a pet,
you're trespassing.
如果你不是宠物
你这是非法侵入。
Time to go!
Get a move on.
是时候出发了！
继续前进。
Wait a minute.
What about our pets?
等一下。
我们的宠物呢？
Oh!
Well, don't worry.
哦！
好吧，别担心。
I'll still be billin' ya
for whatever they eat.
我仍然会向你收费
无论他们吃什么。
all: Whoa!
全体：哇！
[retches]
[干呕]
both: Eww.
两人：呃。
...Hoo, hoo!
- Sandy.
……呼呼！
- 桑迪。
Your Alaskan Bull Worm
certainly was hungry.
你的阿拉斯加牛蠕虫
肯定是饿了。
[gasp]
[喘气]
Sweet jawbone of San Antone,
I'm broke!
圣安东的甜蜜颚骨，
我破产了！
Looks like I'm eatin' canned
nuts for the rest of the year.
看来我在吃罐头
今年剩下的时间里都是坚果。
Ah.
啊。
[animals chatter]
[动物叽叽喳喳]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Welcome, little worm!
欢迎，小虫子！
Here at the Krusty Krab,
在蟹堡王这里，
it's a pet paradise.
- Aaah.
这是一个宠物天堂。
- 啊啊。
♪ ♪
♪♪
Enjoy yourself!
尽情享受吧！
And don't forget to order
something to eat.
并且不要忘记订购
吃点东西。
[barking]
[叫声]
Oh uh, maybe I'll order for you.
噢，也许我可以为你订购。
Heh, heh.
呵呵。
Hey, man.
嘿，伙计。
Could I like...
get a Krabby Patty to go?
我可以喜欢...
去吃蟹肉饼吗？
Sorry.
Pets only.
对不起。
仅限宠物。
You can try your luck across
the street.
你可以试试你的运气
街道。
Aww.
I don't wanna eat chum.
哇。
我不想吃密友。
[laughing]
[笑]
- Rawr!
- [groans]
- 劳尔！
- [呻吟]
[disappointed groaning]
[失望的呻吟]
Heh, heh!
The house special!
呵呵！
房子特别！
Ugh.
啊。
It's great that my pets
are eating and all, but...
我的宠物真是太好了
正在吃东西，但是……
I'm still hungry!
我还饿着呢！
Aww.
哇。
♪ ♪
♪♪
Heh, heh.
呵呵。
[twinkling music]
[闪烁的音乐]
[gulp]
[吞咽]
Mmm.
嗯。
I wish I was a pet
我希望我是一只宠物
so I could eat off the floor.
这样我就可以在地板上吃饭了。
You are eating off the floor.
你正在地板上吃东西。
Yeah, but...
是的，但是...
I wanna eat Krabby Patties
off the floor!
我想吃蟹黄饼
离开地板！
The pink dude might have
the right idea, guys.
粉红色的家伙可能有
正确的想法，伙计们。
If we dress up like pets...
如果我们打扮得像宠物一样……
We could trick Krabs
into serving us!
我们可以欺骗蟹蟹
为我们服务！
Of course!
当然！
If you wanna make costumes,
I have a craft corner.
如果你想制作服装，
我有一个手工角。
Oh, boy!
哦，孩子！
♪ ♪
♪♪
Aaah, plah!
啊啊，普拉！
Oh, construction paper.
Oh, boy!
噢，建筑用纸。
哦，孩子！
[overlapping chatter]
[重叠的喋喋不休]
Anyone seen the glue?
有人见过胶水吗？
[chuckling menacingly]
[威胁地笑]
Now's my chance to sneak
into the Krusty Krab
现在是我潜行的机会
进入蟹堡王
in my pet, Spot.
在我的宠物 Spot 中。
[barking]
[叫声]
[chuckling]
[轻笑]
Hey...
What's happening?
嘿...
发生什么事了？
No, Spot.
Stop digesting me, Spot!
不，斑点。
别再消化我了，现货！
Bad Spot!
坏点！
Yeeoowww!
是啊www！
[barking]
[叫声]
Barnacles.
藤壶。
[accordion music]
[手风琴音乐]
Into the wall ya go!
进墙吧！
[gasps]
What the...?
[喘气]
什么……？
Oh, boy!
I mean... aarf, aarf.
哦，孩子！
我的意思是……阿夫，阿夫。
Hmm...
唔...
Hungry!
饥饿的！
Hmm...
唔...
Ooh, ha, ha.
Ha, ha.
哦，哈哈哈。
哈，哈。
Woof, woof!
汪汪汪！
Hmm.
Squidward!
唔。
章鱼哥！
[grumbles]
[抱怨]
Rawh!
哇！
Yes, Mister... Achoo! Krabs.
是的，先生……阿丘！螃蟹。
Why don't all these new pets
为什么所有这些新宠物都不
have patties in front of 'em?
他们面前有肉饼吗？
I'm running a business,
not a shelter!
我正在经营一家企业，
不是庇护所！
Ow!
噢！
- Mmm.
- Huh?
- 嗯。
- 啊？
Greetings, fellow lagomorph.
哈喽，兔类同胞们。
Perhaps you might consider
sharing a sliver of your...
也许你可以考虑
分享你的一小部分...
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[gasps]
[喘气]
I'll just be...
我就只是...
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[rabbits snarling]
[兔子咆哮]
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
Hahaha!
哈哈哈！
[cheering]
[欢呼]
[all growling]
[全都咆哮]
[blows landing]
[吹着陆]
Pet fight!
宠物大战！
Rah!
啊！
Aaaah!
啊啊啊！
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
[growling and hissing]
[咆哮和嘶嘶声]
Mrowr!
呜呜！
My leg!
我的腿！
[cawing]
[啼叫]
No, no, no.
Bad scallops!
不，不，不。
扇贝坏了！
Aaaah!
啊啊啊！
[crashing]
[崩溃]
[chaotic screaming]
[混乱的尖叫声]
Who's ready for...
谁准备好...
a violent brawl?
暴力斗殴？
Stop, please!
请停一下！
The Krusty Krab
is a place of peace.
蟹堡王
是一个和平的地方。
[growling]
[咆哮]
- Yow!
- 哟！
[growling]
[咆哮]
Dah!
呸！
[gasps]
The health inspector?
[喘气]
卫生督察？
all: The health inspector?
全体：卫生督察？
Eh...
Roar?
呃……
咆哮？
But I thought you said people
and pets can't eat together?
但我以为你说的是人
和宠物不能一起吃饭吗？
Yeah.
What are you doing here?
是的。
你在这里做什么？
This whole mess is your fault!
这一切的混乱都是你的错！
[crowd clamoring]
[人群喧闹]
Em, I was just hungry
for a Krabby Patty.
Em，我只是饿了
蟹肉饼。
We've all been there, right?
我们都去过那里，对吧？
Plus, I, um, I learned
something today!
另外，我，嗯，我学到了
今天有事！
SpongeBob, give me
a bouncy C, would ya?
海绵宝宝，给我
一个有弹性的C，好吗？
Ooo, gladly!
噢噢，很高兴！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[lively music]
[活泼的音乐]
♪ Pets are people too ♪
♪ 宠物也是人 ♪
♪ Just like me, just like you ♪
♪ 就像我一样，就像你一样 ♪
♪ Yes, whatever
you like to do ♪
♪ 是的，无论如何
你喜欢做的事♪
♪ There's a pet
who likes it too ♪
♪ 有一只宠物
谁也喜欢♪
♪ There's a pet for people
who like to run ♪
♪ 人们有一只宠物
喜欢跑步的人♪
♪ And one for people
who don't ♪
♪ 一款为人们服务的
谁不喜欢♪
♪ A pet for folks
who avoid the sun ♪
♪ 适合人们的宠物
躲避阳光的人♪
♪ And those who should
but won't ♪
♪ 以及那些应该
但不会♪
♪ A pet for people
who sing and dance ♪
♪ 人类的宠物
又唱又跳的人♪
♪ A pet for people who cry ♪
♪ 适合哭泣的人的宠物 ♪
♪ A pet for people
who take a chance ♪
♪ 人类的宠物
谁抓住机会♪
♪ And for those
with just one eye ♪
♪ 对于那些
只有一只眼睛♪
♪ Yes, no matter what
we say or do ♪
♪ 是的，无论如何
我们说或做♪
♪ There's just one thing
I know is true ♪
♪ 只有一件事
我知道这是真的♪
♪ We all eat patties,
yes we do! ♪
♪ 我们都吃肉饼，
是的，我们愿意！ ♪
♪ And every pet likes
eating them too! ♪
♪ 每只宠物都喜欢
也吃它们！ ♪
♪ Because ♪
♪ 因为 ♪
all:
♪ Pets are people too ♪
全部：
♪ 宠物也是人 ♪
♪ Just like me, just like you ♪
♪ 就像我一样，就像你一样 ♪
♪ Yes, whatever
you like to do ♪
♪ 是的，无论如何
你喜欢做的事♪
♪ There's a pet
who's just like you ♪
♪ 有一只宠物
谁和你一样 ♪
♪ Just like you! ♪
♪ 就像你一样！ ♪
♪ Pets! ♪
♪ 宠物！ ♪
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Whew!
哇！
Pets and people deserve to eat
side by side.
宠物和人都应该吃饭
并排。
Ahee!
啊嘿！
Yes!
是的！
And a round of patties
for everyone!
还有一圈肉饼
对于每个人！
Not on the house!
不是在房子上！
[cheering]
[欢呼]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[indistinct chatter]
[模糊的喋喋不休]
Gosh, mister.
天哪，先生。
You've got more customers
here than I've ever seen!
你有更多的客户
这里比我见过的还要多！
'Course I do!
我当然愿意！
Didn't you hear the song?
你没听到这首歌吗？
♪ Pets are people too ♪
♪ 宠物也是人 ♪
Well if they count as people...
好吧，如果他们也算人的话……
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
Then they count as fire hazards!
那么它们就被视为火灾隐患！
I'm the fire marshal, and
you're over capacity, Krabs.
我是消防队长
你已经超出容量了，蟹蟹。
Shut her down!
关掉她！
Everyone out!
大家都出去吧！
What?
什么？
Nooo!
不！
[all grumbling]
[大家都在抱怨]
Wait.
Come back, come back!
等待。
回来吧，回来吧！
Me pet profits.
我宠物利润。
I'm ruined.
我毁了。
Hey, uh...
Mr. Krabs?
嘿，呃...
蟹老板？
I was planning
on taking a Krabby Patty
我本来计划
吃蟹肉饼
home to my Gare Bear.
我的加雷熊的家。
You could overcharge me
for it if you want.
你可以多收我的钱
如果你愿意的话。
Eh, huh.
Really?
呃，呵呵。
真的吗？
Thanks, boy-o!
谢谢，小伙子！
You're a good minimum wage employee.
你是一名优秀的最低工资雇员。
Yaaaah!
[crashing]
啊啊啊！
[崩溃]
Ahh, hah.
啊哈。
♪ ♪
♪♪
Aaaachoo!
啊啊啊！
Pah, ah!
Urgh!
呸，啊！
呃！